In this world...
Is the destiny of mankind controlled by some transcendental entity or law?
Is it like the hand of God hovering above?
At least it is true...
...that man has no control, even over his own will.
T-This is...
The Egg of the King!
I see!
So that's the ploy...
It's your fault...
You put Griffith in danger
and almost got him killed...
It's all your fault!
Feel no shame about shape
Weather changes their phrase
Even mother will show you another way
So put your glasses on
Nothing will be wrong
There's no blame. There's no fame
It's up to you
The first words should be found
Whatever holds you back
I...
...can...
I can get it off
Tell me what...
Tell me what you want
I don't know why...
Don't know why...
Don't know why you're afraid
Tell me what...
Tell me what you'd say
I don't know why...
Don't know why...
Too late...
It's too late
The Sword's Owner
Have you heard about
the Band of the Hawk?
I have...
They suffered serious
losses during a recent battle.
I can't say for certain, but...
...soldiers claim they met some
huge demon in Tudor Castle.
A huge demon?
I declare it to be a falsehood...
...designed to draw attention
away from their failure.
It's no better than a child's trick!
However, Griffith ultimately succeeded
in securing the castle's surrender.
Even if they did suffer serious losses,
we may not accuse them of failure.
Besides, it is rumored that
Griffith will be raised to the peerage.
Aye, I've heard that as well.
Really, it is true?
His reputation with the king keeps
rising due to his recent achievements.
This is very irritating!
Why should the king give
that title to a mercenary?
He is...
The commander of their raiders...
You've had a terrible experience in battle.
I heard that you encountered
a demon on the battlefield.
I wonder if it was
the demon that injured you?
Perhaps you saw a dog in the dark
and thought it was a monster.
That is likely!
Y-You...
Sorry, I'm unsteady on
my feet because of my wounds.
D-Damn you!
My blade hungers for you...
Bastard...
Guts!
What's going on?
You're all out here.
Are you well enough to walk?
Yeah...
It's all your fault!
Just forget it.
No one blames you.
Casca just said that because
she was frantic back there.
And what are you up to?
We want to visit Griffith.
But...
There are visitors here already.
Ministers and bishops,
big shots in the royal court...
The world is as kind
as it is cruel, so to speak.
Some of the senior statesmen
despise Griffith and regard him...
...as an upstart mercenary commoner.
Meanwhile, others try to gain his
favor to secure their future in the court.
I get it...
Maybe we've just been
taking it for granted...
...but Griffith has been invincible so far.
Basically, he is the leader of
the strongest unit in Midland's army.
Well, then...
Where to?
Hey!
Wait!
You weren't listening, were you?
I was.
So what?
Don't give me that!
I'm telling you to wait here until
Griffith finishes receiving his guests.
That doesn't matter at all.
I just want to visit an injured friend.
Guts!
I'm going!
You are not allowed in!
Please wait until the meeting is over.
You...
Sorry.
Big idiot...
Rickert, will you come with me?
T-That's all right...
Okay...
Hey, Griffith...
I'm sick of this.
Stop trying to...
What's the meaning of this?
Why?
Why are you always like this?
Why does Griffith value you so much?
Hey, Guts!
That spoiled everything.
I'll come back later!
I think...
I understand Guts's feelings somewhat.
After all, Griffith has been
unapproachable lately...
He's been like a stranger...
You...
...should have been killed
by Griffith back there!
You don't care at all about your men.
You're just a mad dog!
Why...
Why are you always like this?
It's all your fault!
Shit!
What the hell does she mean?
My, you're on edge.
Griffith.
You seem to be able
to wield your sword...
...despite the fact you were beaten
much more soundly than I was.
You are quite a tough one.
I apologize about yesterday.
I heard everyone came to visit me.
Taking advantage of my injury...
...those ministers condescendingly
visit me every single day.
To be honest, they are truly annoying.
I'm without any choice, however.
Nosferatu Zodd...
To think that such an enormous
monster really exists...
Part of me feels as if that encounter
was some kind of nightmare.
But on the other hand...
...it's evident such a giant exists...
...even though it's beyond human knowledge.
I would say...
...that it might be something like a god.
It was more like a demon, wasn't it?
Who knows?
It's all the same.
By the way, how was I saved?
I passed out in the middle of the fight.
It was because of
that thing around your neck.
If you and this man truly regard each
other as friends, be mindful of this...
When this man's ambition crumbles...
...you will be destined to face your death!
A death you can never escape!
Zodd certainly recognized that thing...
This seems to protect me from evil.
I've got to thank that old
fortune-teller woman.
I think...
I owe you again.
Tell me why.
Three years ago...
...you told me that you didn't
want to lose an outstanding soldier.
I am just a warrior serving you.
But you were about
to lose your life for me...
...a mere soldier.
It's not the kind of thing that
happens to a levelheaded guy like you.
Why?
Oh dear, I thought we
finished up that talk three years ago.
There's no reason...
...in particular.
Do you want a reason?
Do you really need a reason...
...each time I decide to lay
my life on the line for you?
No, I just...
Oh, Sir White Hawk.
You seem to have gotten better.
Your Majesty!
Hey, Guts!
How dare you be discourteous
in His Majesty's presence!
Never mind that. Raise your heads.
I'm just getting some air.
But, Your Majesty...
Everybody in the castle
has grown excited because...
...of all the war councils.
Alas, I do not have time
to regain my composure.
Let me introduce you...
This is my younger brother, Count Julius.
He's the general of the White Dragons
and next in line to the throne.
I am Griffith.
Pleased to make your acquaintance.
My lord Griffith...
I am always proud when you capably
lead the Band of the Hawk to victory.
That is very kind.
Forgetting my old age,
your dauntless courage in battle...
...even makes me burn for a fight!
It reminds me of those days of my youth...
...when I worked alongside
my subjects in the war effort.
Majesty, I must object to this
addressing of a mere unit commander.
I do not mind talking with him.
The truth be told...
...some senior statesmen in the royal
court are displeased by your presence.
Alarmed by your influence...
...they are concerned
that your common birth...
...might affect the prestige
of the Midland army.
However, neither prestige
nor status brings us triumph...
...much less welfare for my people.
We live in a turbulent age.
Hence, I am greatly depending upon
exceptional people like yourself...
...rather than aristocratic generals
who are tied up in old traditions...
...for I am committed to building
a strong foundation for my land.
Once again, I am very much
obliged to Your Majesty.
Who is that lady over there?
Oh...
She is my daughter, Charlotte.
She is very shy.
According to her, she is
frightened of haughty warriors...
...so she rarely comes out of the palace.
Charlotte, come over here.
She is a very private person.
That is because she is my
only daughter, so I spoil her.
Forgive her, Lord Griffith.
Come along now, Charlotte.
Pardon me.
Be careful, my lady.
You bastard!
Such discourtesy,
touching the princess's body!
Hey, old man!
Pardon my improper manner...
...Your Excellency Julius.
What's keeping you?
Oh, it's nothing, Father.
We shall go, my lady.
Do you really need a reason...
...each time I decide to lay
my life on the line for you?
He said, "For you"...
I don't know if this is the answer
I've been looking for all my life.
But for now...
I will fight with my sword for him!
All right, everyone!
Do you understand how
important this stronghold is?
No, sir!
Idiots!
You should know your history!
Listen, due to our capture of Doldrey,
for the first time we were able...
...to successfully split the enemy lines.
Afterwards, this stronghold
was built as our army's...
...staging point for attacks against Midland.
Behold this road!
This road once functioned as the
most important pass for military troops...
...between Doldrey and
the kingdom's territory.
However, since our military
forces seized this bridge...
...the tide of the war turned.
They were forced...
...to expose the heart of Midland
directly before our military forces.
According to the secret tactics...
...handed down
the Coborlwitz family for 300 years...
...capture a road and you will capture victory.
To capture victory,
we should strengthen our defenses...
My defense is already planned!
Look...
If the enemy attacks us,
they have to march over this bridge.
Therefore, the best soldiers from
the garrison will amass on the bridge.
It's a narrow stone bridge...
...so only a mounted soldier
or two can charge at a time.
Moreover, Tudor's best crossbowmen...
...will be standing by
above the exterior gate.
Our crossbowmen will definitely
cut down the enemy leaders...
...as they march one by one.
It's perfect!
We'll deliver a severe blow to the enemy...
...and thanks to my fantastic scheme,
we'll escape any damage!
You can trust me on this!
But what if the enemy doesn't use
this bridge and attacks our flanks?
You need not worry.
There is no bridge or ford along
the river within eight miles of here.
And the river is so wide and deep that
even the best horse could not cross.
B-But what if the enemy
makes a raft, and...
As you can see, we are in a barren
land of rocks and vineyards.
It is impossible to make rafts
because there aren't enough trees.
Even if the enemy made what
they could with the nearby trees...
...they wouldn't be able to send
enough of their troops over at once.
Or will they make rafts
out of the grapevines?
Why do we have to sortie
the minute Griffith gets better?
They depend on us in battle.
But didn't they say...
...even the heavily equipped Golem
Knights failed to capture that castle?
I heard they suffered severely.
Reportedly, two thirds of the knights
were defeated on the bridge.
What, are you serious?
It's our turn.
We'll dispose of them.
Looking back, the morning comes.
Don't find your face in your glass.
Take the moonlight by the tail.
It's a rainy sight. You're shading.
What is that?
It's just the same.
What is trying your crown?
I'm spending my glass, walking back.
So wear my glass. You're fading.
I'm waiting so long.
I'm waiting...